pressprogress.ca 2019-06-25

# PressProgress

### ​PressProgress respects your privacy

Our resources and publications are provided as a free service to the public and can therefore be accessed free of charge and do not require your personal information to do so.

Any and all personal information you voluntarily provide is protected under the provisions of Canada’s federal privacy legislation.

We collect personally identifiable information from individuals when it is provided voluntarily and knowingly, such as through our e-newsletter subscriptions, donation forms or online petitions.

We also collect non-personal and aggregate information from our site visitors.

We automatically log information about visits to this website in the normal course of establishing and maintaining web connections. Our servers record statistical information such as visitors’ IP addresses, time and duration of visit, and web pages visited.

Like most websites, ours uses “cookies” to obtain non-personal information from site visitors (small data files that your web browser places on your computer when you visit a website). Most browsers accept cookies automatically, but can be configured not to accept them or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. That is up to you to set up.

PressProgress does not extract personal information in this process, nor do we sell this information to third parties. Cookies allow us to speed up the navigation process and to make the website experience more efficient; they also help us measure the traffic on our website so that we can assess the effectiveness of our education and outreach efforts.

If you choose to provide personal information in order to sign up for our e-newsletter, make a donation or sign an online petition, we will only use that information as follows:

### Email Communication

Our weekly email updates are designed to share the work and helpful resources provided by PressProgress. We also occasionally ask subscribers to consider making a donation. If you do sign up for our email updates, we will never share or disclose your email address to third party. All emails include an unsubscribe option that users can use at any time to stop receiving emails.

### Online Donors

If you make a donation to PressProgress using our convenient online form, your email address and credit card information will be handled with extreme confidentiality.

### Security is our top priority

PressProgress has taken steps to keep all information received from our online visitors as secure as possible against unauthorized access and use. All personal information you provide is stored in a secure database; your credit card information is only used to process your order and is not stored beyond the point at which your payment is approved. All online payments are processed securely and protected by Secure Socket Layer (SSL).

### Feel free to touch base

Do not hesitate to email PressProgress at info [at] PressProgress [dot] ca if you wish to:

  * access, correct or add to your personal information that we maintain
  * make a complaint regarding the management of your personal information
  * be removed from any of our mailing lists or database(s)
